oh my God Sam what is wrong with you you
know normal things that everybody does
well that made it honestly though that
made it affordable that made it so that
I for run you know dude the amount of
time you spent rewriting that TLS
Library cost you more than that freaking
compute power ever would uh I don't know
I was I was scanning the entire internet
for like 20 bucks a month like it
[Music]
nothing
hey guys check this out there's a bug
bounding program right now that is
paying 6.25 times it's normal Bounty
amounts it's brand new and the scope is
so massive that there's practically a 0%
chance of dupes and it's a white box
testing environment so you've got access
to source code this is a bug Hunter's
dream come true and it's the word fence
bug bounty program get this the scope
for this program is every single
WordPress plugin above 50k installs so
there's thousands of plugins already and
it's expanding every single day it's a
crazy opportunity and the team knows
it's frankly a little crazy so they had
to put a cap on the number of reports a
researcher can have active at a given
time and they kept it at five but for
you the critical thinking listener
thanks to the sponsorship you guys get
20 active reports at a time and you'll
get an extra 10% bonus on top of your
report When you mention critical
thinking for your first submission to
the word fence spoke bouny program so
it's an amazing opportunity head over to
ctbb show/ WF cb. WF for word fence and
get more information submit some crazy
bugs I know you guys are going to crush
it all right let's get to the
episode Al righty we got a super special
guest today Mr Sam BB welcome to the
podcast man hi um longtime listener
first time color yay dude
that's great well thanks for coming on
man and I appreciate you listening I do
I do know that you do listen because
you'll ping me from time to time and and
talk about stuff uh from the Pod so
definitely definitely appreciate that
yeah yeah I you know this is this is on
my rotation you know and I'm like doing
dishes or showering I don't know listen
to this showering yeah the best
time um true you got to get those those
shower thoughts in you know oh yeah yeah
man yeah it's actually been really cool
too you know that that because we've I
think uh H said Shopify Spotify has been
coming out with those uh you know like
what is it
2002 wrapped yeah thing and people have
been like oh you know we listen to
critical thinking all the time you know
top whatever percent listeners so
definitely definitely appreciate that um
so so I guess normally at the beginning
of this podcast we will go into like
little history of Sam you know and that
sort of thing um but I think we're going
to skip that this time and we're going
to come back to it later and we're just
going to jump right into some hacker
methodology stuff okay because so just
for okay right I'll do a little context
all right a little context tell tell the
people who we're talking to all right so
this is this is Sam MB currently Google
employee uh hacker extraordinaire one of
my top respected hackers uh and one of
the most influential hackers in in my
life as far as um you know methodology
and like uh I guess hacking techniques
that I respect
uh as far as that goes so Sam I'm really
happy to have you here um and and I kind
of want to dive a little bit into what
makes you um so special as as a buck
Bounty Hunter and a hacker and my theory
is that that is largely coming from a
background that is not related to web
security right um so talk to talk to me
a little bit because you you were a
low-level I guess you were doing
lowlevel development right uh in the
beginning or was it always security you
know I know you were working with stuff
that was not web web related yeah so
it's always been web tangential I think
is the best way to describe it um and
security tangential but I have spent a
decade as a developer um yeah so I
worked at uh Cisco for a few years doing
uh crypto Hardware integration yeah so
this is exactly the [__] I'm talking
about like cry crypto Hardware
integration you know like a question um
okay so so I guess
I I want to hear about that and we're
going to we're going to hear about that
but what what I really want to get to is
why is this whole concept of going wide
and versus going deep and I I categorize
hackers by this right and you hear me
talk about this on the pot all the time
you are very much a go deep sort of
hacker by my estimation um and so I want
I'm wondering is that a do you think
that's a function of you know having
spent so much time at a lower level that
you're more comfortable at the lower
level so you try to get down lower and
lower and lower and lower or um you know
is that an intentional decision made by
you that's a really good question
I I think there is a certain amount of
like I I am comfortable going and
reading an RFC and then you know
applying that somewhere and trying
everything that I can find in the RFC um
but at the same time it's you know
I having been a developer it's like you
you kind of you know what mistakes like
to me anyways you know what dis makes
mistakes developers make and then you
can go and uh find those mistakes the
Wild and you know on the the security
engineering side of that it's like how
do you prevent those mistakes from
happening um or build Frameworks that
don't allow them um but yeah I mean
you've seen it it's you know there's
there's there's been a lot of instances
where like I think that there should be
a bug there and you know I will spend
know 10 hours going off and reading RFC
which is just like you know
completely it's not the healthiest thing
in the world but it's like once you get
fixated on something might be vulnerable
then like it's hard to think about other
things yeah for sure do do you think
that like also your engineering sort of
like background has pushed you to be
more of like a technical Hunter rather
than sort of like that blackbox hunting
like I think a lot of the hacking that
I've seen you do sort of is diving into
like how does the source code for this
work or like reading through like the
sort of the the more um open open source
sort of sort of approach and do you feel
like your engineering side has really
pushed you in that direction and as well
yeah absolutely like I I want to
understand how the systems work to break
them um the story that I tell actually a
lot is like this was at like one of the
US government life hacking events um
somebody from the US government was like
you know asked me and a few other
hackers is like you know how do you guys
avoid the dark side you
know how do you say how do you say good
hackers and I was personally I was so
offended by that cuz like all I want to
do is go and figure out how these
systems work and break them it's like I
don't care what your social security
number is you know yeah yeah no that how
do sense yeah how do you not commit
credit card fraud what's going on yeah
and I'm like maybe that's what you want
to do and like that's you know but
that's not why I'm here yeah no and and
I think that speaks largely to the
Curiosity motivated aspect uh of and and
I think that's one of the things that
makes you a really a really great
researcher and a really great bug Bounty
Hunter but it does come with that
downside like you mentioned of like all
right I'm gonna read this thing till my
eyes bleed you know and like and and try
to figure out you know Never Letting Go
of a bug especially you know if you
can't figure out if you can't explain
everything in the situation um yeah I um
I love the term uh accidentally secure
yeah because there's things that'll come
across where term I know it but I know
things are
broken in some way but in bug Bounty
context you can only report things that
are valid you know you can't report like
half a bug really well you could but
You' get yeah so so along that line like
H how do you go about sort of thinking
about bugs when when you're when you're
approaching a problem and you want to
like really deep dive and like find sort
of the most impact what is like what is
your thought
process I honestly and I think you guys
have seen this at um some recent events
it's like I'm really interested in
looking for locations where
um uh you can get the highest CVSs score
I think is the best way to describe it
like looking for those un authenticated
places with
[Music]
um you know networks authenticated no
privileges required um you know get aim
for that CVSs 10.0 and avoid the places
where like you you can't possi get that
um you know I had to say it but like
mobile apps come to
mind wow shots fired time like mobile
apps should have a separate my opinion
anyway it should be rewarded differently
yeah to no totally I totally agree we we
we actually had this problem recently as
well where where we were trying to award
a a mobile vulnerability and try and
figure out how to score it and like if
you go traditional CVSs you run into all
these problems where it's like you know
like adjacency is like physical or like
local right it's like it's really like
it's very very difficult um to score in
the same way but like do you do you
actually approach it like from a CVSs
perspective like purely do you just go
sort of like okay like if I were to
think about this from CVSs like what
parts of the app should I avoid or is it
is it more sort of like high
level I mean to be fair that's where
I'll start okay um you know from there
I'll kind of like work my way down um
yeah but
it's yeah you know at the end of the day
it's like we're
we're all trying to like as bug Hunters
anyways we're trying to maximize reward
and yeah that's how we do it well and
and and it's like you know this kind of
reminds me of of a talk I gave a while
back on um you know open source
methodology on the when I was talking
about the graan bug At aam Con it's this
concept of like okay I've got this goal
you know and I I need to I need to work
back from where you know let's say I
want to submit a a you know a 10.0 c CVS
as bug right and was which we all do in
in bug Bounty and also specifically in
life hacking events then you've got to
start naturally from the spots where
it's possible for you to get a you know
a a 10.0 CVSs bug right so it makes more
sense to to focus on the unauthenticated
context and actually I had a little bit
of a of a question here is it seems to
me like in in um in the Life hacking
event that we collaborated on I'll I'll
say it but we're going to have to bleep
it um that uh you know you focused a lot
on authentication there and you focused
a lot on authentication at the last
couple live hacking events that I've
seen you on is that would you say that's
your bread and butter I mean what where
where does that play a role in your
testing you know I always say it's where
I'm going to
start and I just often never move
on that's that's a lot of the truth to
it is like I'll spend like you know next
thing I'll know is it'll be like 20 30
hours later and I'm like I'm still
trying to figure out all the all the
pieces and um understand how they all
mesh together
so when you find yourself down like a
rabbit hole like that do you find it's
more that just like you've you've sort
of stumbled into the fact that the app
is more complicated than you initially
realized or do you keep coming up with
like new more creative scenarios that
you have to sort of sus out and see if
there there are you know viable viable
vulnerabilities I mean it's a little bit
of both but like you know listening to
kind of going back to like listening to
this podcast while I'm like doing other
things like M there's a lot of times
where you know I'll spend like an entire
night just looking at like a single like
a single piece of the application and
then you know go and brush my teeth and
be like Oh I'm an idiot you know I need
to go back there and try these things I
didn't quite realize this is how they
all fit together and um yeah that's
often led to my best bugs so so it been
you know it seems like uh you know to
use the technical terms is funny because
my wife always gets on my case you know
for using Tech Tech terms for like
non-technical things but it's almost
like you know you've got like a you know
like a a like what's the a screen you
know like in the terminal you know like
it's it's running in the back of your
brain you know just like all right let
me just screen detach from that right
and uh and it's just running back there
like processing processing processing
and um and and I think you see that with
a lot of of top bugani Hunters is like
even if you're walking away you know
from the screen when you're doing stuff
like brushing your teeth or like
changing your clothes or like you know
you know you're thinking you're thinking
you're in that mode um and it gets
overwhelming right like that's something
that that really takes a lot of a lot of
the parts of your life and as somebody
who's not a full-time bount bug Bounty
Hunter somebody who has a full-time job
um I'm
wondering how you you manage that you
know with your full-time job and with
bug Bounty and like you know H how does
that affect your life and how do you
segment bug Bounty from these other
things to because it kind of like tries
to take over sometimes I think I mean
it's a really good question I to be
honest I don't do it I don't do too much
bug Bounty work anymore um I used to
participate in every life hacking event
and like you know as um you know my my
partner was off uh finishing off her PhD
for a while and that just gave me a
little bit more free time um because she
was finishing that and so um you know
really since then I've had significantly
less time from that um I will say though
it's
like for me anyways it was most
challenging
to not associate time spent elsewhere
with like a dollars per
hour um like you have to be really
careful like once you start doing this
with any consistency you start getting
paid with any consistency that you don't
associate your time with an hourly rate
because all of a sudden like and
honestly to be clearly honest I still
have a lot of trouble just sit down
watching TV
like yeah that's just a challenge
because like I'll start thinking like oh
hey like I actually I call this
um I call it like it's almost like a
metronome in the back of my head that's
like you know tick tick tick so I call
it like a tick almost like why are you
know you should be doing this like why
are you hanging out with your friends
you should be going making money like
yeah yeah yeah and so like to have you
have to to me anyways it's important
to not even try and calculate that cuz
once I start going down that route it's
it it can really drive me to netive
outcomes it's a slippery slope for sure
you know we talked about it you know on
the episode a little bit with Douglas
with Douglas day with Archangel um and
he you know he was saying yeah like now
I'm try trying to find it hard to like
justify you know going out with my
friends instead of staying home and
hacking you know when you have this
essentially unlimited access to trade
your time for for money that's not
really limited and sometimes it's like
huge amounts of money I mean to be fair
it's a good problem like it's a very
privilege problem to have it is it is
and and and and I'm grateful for it but
you know when you swing it the other way
it's a little bit you know it becomes
destructive um and so it's hard for bug
bounty hunters to to regulate that for
sure um definitely a pitfall to be aware
of so so jumping back to the the the
hacking methodology thing I'm wondering
you know being a deep diving hacker I
kind of get crap all the time uh from
the community for like yeah you know
I'll spend like three three weeks four
weeks on a program you know before I
like move on I'm wondering I'm looking
for some validation here no how long do
you spend on a program and how long do
you uh how deep do you dive you know
also again Let Me Cave out that question
though because I know that you know the
brain works a little better for Mr Sam
compared to to me so it may not take you
quite as long to to get through a Target
but I have I don't know so when it comes
to life hacking events especially I will
look at that Target nothing but that
Target for oh yeah that time period and
then just stop completely um for other
targets I will actually come back to
them especially targets that I'll submit
a bug and they'll react to it quickly
like that's been my test it's like if I
subit a bug they react to it quickly
like okay like this this team isn't
going to have like too many uh
duplicates sitting around for me to find
um they're quick to respond which means
like I can go and submit other things
and not not be worried that they're
going to like I don't know maybe not pay
me or something for example um sure but
honestly there have been very few PR
targets that I've like really stuck with
um Airbnb was one that I um and I think
we we actually participated in that life
hacking event together yes we did
Sam yes we did and I behind me yeah I
took yeah okay I took first at that
event but somehow somebody else got the
belt so love
that um no we'll dive into that later
I'm sorry continue but everyb was one
where it's like
I I found that I really liked how their
application worked and um you know so I
did the extra step there I even
automated everything that I could um and
I really stuck with that for years until
they made some like pretty high level
they actually wrote a whole engineering
blog post on on this and it was like
more of like an engineering change but
it also resulted in like a really
positive security outcome where like all
of their security became much more
centralized and really
bug prone to describe it um dude can you
talk a little bit about that like now
that the blog post is out can you talk
about some of the details of what they
changed and and well this this is
entirely from an outside perspective
like I don't know any the like you know
Insider details of any of this obviously
um but you know
they without I'm trying to like not talk
about bug reports sorry um you're good
uh they centralized seemingly Central a
lot of their good yeah well for what
it's worth if you want to talk about
some bug reports we can always like cut
it out and bleep it later so that makes
easier yeah oh no it's all good I really
think like what it comes down to is like
they really centralize their um off
management and
that really like putting that all into
one place and
like centralizing control of all their
API end points um really led to it was
really it seems like it was more of an
engineering decision you know like it
probably led to good engineering
outcomes but the side effect was like
you didn't have teams going off and
making their own apis with the same
mistakes over and over again um so you
know that after that I kind of stopped
what ises that so what does that mean
Sam like like if we were to if we were
to take it a little another layer you
know clearer is that saying okay you
know they implemented some middleware
that sits on front of all the API
endpoints that implements you know their
access control stuff and all of the ey
doors disappeared or are we talking
about off I mean is that is that
talk
yeah yeah I don't want
that no I mean like we can say that
Airbnb had idors you know it's not that
that's not the end of the world um no
and that that's big you know and so when
you see a giant change like that you
know that changed the way that you
interacted with that with that program
um subti it's a good security outcome
for them um you know we're
obviously uh you know we're we're
we're both simultaneously like security
driven but we're also monetarily driven
so it's like yeah obviously it resulted
in me getting paid less money but it
also means being more secure so so how
long did you spend on that program uh oh
I mean I automated everything I could um
probably 50 to 100 hours okay and is
that over the course of six months is
that over the course of a couple weeks a
few months okay and what does automation
for that sort of thing look like
everything was custom um you know I was
I was running custom parsers for their
JavaScript to pull out API end points
testing those API end points um I were
you automatically testing the API end
points were you alerting on them then
manually text test usually just manually
alerting to be fair but um there was
there was some automation there uh then
there was also um I've gone through a
series of like revisions of my own like
Recon architecture um some of which I
ended up open sourcing um but uh I that
was is that on your GitHub uh I don't
actually know if I ever uh well I mean
part of it was that was the whole like
DNS SCP thing ah yeah yeah yeah DNS
scrap yeah yeah of course so that's just
like you know you can take advantage of
uh you know DNS is hierarchical you can
search it really easily based on that um
as long as you pre sort it yeah yeah
yeah I was going to ask so like two
things on that one you mentioned that
you wrote like very custom automation um
obviously that's a little bit when you
have a software engineering background
but was that something sort of
like that you decided to do because you
were spending a lot of time on Airbnb or
do you do that for every program or like
what what what made you do this guy
freaking probably wrote it in
C to be fair was using like four
languages but yeah no c in there
what I'm I don't even want to know get
get out you're off the pot not allowed
oh jeez no just you know I try to use
the right thing for the right purpose
like you know I spring over together
with bash but like where I need to I'll
drop into like goang to just get things
faster and yeah I'm not I'm not quite at
rest yet but I'll get there eventually
yeah well few of us are um no that makes
sense and actually JS monitoring is
something that we've been talking about
a lot in the you know critical thinking
Community lately and there have been
some really cool solutions that are
coming up around it and uh it's it's
exciting to see and you know you were
kind of ahead of the of the curve on
this industry you know doing this back
in what I mean when did we compete at
that event was that 2018 may have been
2019 yeah yeah yeah 2019 maybe
um so you
know what was that I mean let me just
try to break it down technically so you
would you would reach out to the you
know uh HTML page pull out the
Javascript file hash go to that
Javascript file would you beautify it or
would you just run rex on on it or were
you were you doing diffs of of the code
directly or were you doing diffs of like
the strings in the code how did that
look um if I recall correctly it was
like a I think webpack is the right term
to be us in there yeah so Reach Out P
the web pack uh they followed and I once
again this is pushing
my they would a little further back
too um they would uh follow a very
common format mhm for their API points
in that web pack even though it was
somewhat minified um which you could
then pretty straightforward to a stct
that and yeah I mean from there it's all
just like Discord notifications like hey
there's this new thing and you know it's
it's a really easy way to when you when
you know a program well it can become a
very easy way to find bugs um because as
soon as something launches you just be
like okay I'm just going to go test it
you know and you're off to the first one
there yeah 100% I mean this is what the
PRS are doing you know when you're when
you're going longterm going deep on a
program and and that actually makes me
think a little bit for you know more
obviously you were sort of taking notes
with code in this scenario right you
were you were saying okay I've noticed
this structure in the JS file on how
these API endpoints are you know done
I'm going to write some code to
automatically parsel this and you know
uh help me see this in a better way but
I'm wondering what kind of notes do you
take for yourself in general are you
like a you know whatever a.txt sort of
guy or you like I've got this whole
Postman built out with their whole API
spec sort of guy um on I did I did hear
that in the last episode that's that's
wild yeah it's ni for for me I actually
take I have like a pretty standardized
format at this point for Recon I think
all my Recon is up at his own folder
everything is very very neat there and I
can even diff it between like runs um to
see what's new but when it comes to like
looking at the application itself no I
yeah I'm going read me.txt guy yeah sure
sure sure next time next time I hack on
this.xd yeah I mean like what do you
think about that though like just out of
curiosity you know we all have the
things that we do you know because we
that's just how we do it but but do you
think it'd be more optimal for you to
take time to to to write you know more
thorough notes or do you think that
would interrupt the creative process or
what I think it you know I think it
really depends like I think it like it's
easier maybe case again like I think
like if I were to spend more time on
that program than yeah I would
absolutely have taken much more
structured notes on that and I have a
lot of respect for folks who do and
like I don't know that's something I
should I should get better
at yeah yeah there's definitely room for
growth yeah I mean I I thought I had
structured notes and then even even
still I've seen some other people who
have like way way more structured notes
and I'm like I'm looking at theirs and
I'm like dang that's I I need to make
some improvements and then every time I
go back to mine I'm like uh this would
be a lot better if I if I had you know X
Y and Z but um it's just one of those
things that is is sometimes it's a real
big time investment and uh depending on
like what your workflow looks like like
if it's not like a bump in your workflow
then oftentimes it's just better to just
you know keep it simple and yeah I think
it was I think it was the the interview
with France which like I don't know I
feel kind of honored to have to go in
after
him St treig choose to fill um but uh he
he talked about how he was like
uh you know taking taking notes of like
parameters used and stuff and it's like
I almost wish I had even like a whole
another layer of structured Recon um
because usually I for the most part
anyways I tend to stop with like sub
enumeration a little bit past that but
like not too much and like I really
think that there's so much that could be
added there um that would you know at
the end day just like
make make the bunk hunter's life easier
so to speak yeah yeah yeah there's
there's a lot of uh extra layers you can
go down deep and when you get start
getting diminishing returns I don't know
and it actually makes me makes me think
of this this topic um this sort of
hypothesis that I've been kind of
thinking about lately because you know
us three we've all been successful in
bug bouny and you know when you start
building a Discord Community like we are
at critical thinking you get a lot of
people being like hey you know this is
what I want to do can can you help me
get there and I and we don't have time
to answer all the questions but um I it
it has made me think think more about
how to framework eyes what I do right
and and how to like take away life
lessons from something that I just kind
of do intuitively right um and one of
the things that came to my mind is I
wonder whether bug bounty hunting can be
minimized to or or simplified I guess to
number of attack vectors tried like I I
wonder if if there was a way for us to
optimize our hunting for just raw number
of attack vectors tried whether that
would be close to the optimal path to
produce uh you know bugs as the result
like like am I am I off base here what I
think you're off base I'm not lie that's
great that's good good day would just
would just dominate that chart right or
something you know right the what the
what would dominate that Z day or like
an inex zero day oh yeah no no I mean
like well what what do you mean by that
because I mean like okay you know I'm
GNA try if I can do this idor on this
one end point no okay you know I'm GNA
do try to do this you know uh se- surf
over here you know like the more attack
factures I'm trying the more likelihood
one of them is going to work right and
and so but I guess this is sort of
approach this is gy right here okay all
right hit attack you try the equally
likely they are for for them to pop okay
it's a flip of a coin every single time
there's no guarantee but it's not though
like it's not really well abstract like
from it abstractly yes there's no like
every vulnerability has an equal chance
of of of occurring depending on the
context and you with your intuition as a
hunter you can determine what things are
more likely I'm talk so I think that
that's like like the real Nuance is that
the more that you've been hacking the
more you're able to narrow like quickly
narrow down your scope of
vulnerabilities that you're testing
based on what you're see being whereas
theoretically there's infinite
possibilities right like you you could
test infinite variations of idors and
vulnerabilities in all different
parameters and everything and never hit
anything because you're sort of blindly
testing the wrong things when you should
be doing what you're doing which is
narrowly targeting it down yeah and so
I've actually this has like a lot of
parallel with um like binary vers
engineering um and like the the thing
I've heard there anyways is like I not
great at this myself but like we're
going to get some samur [__] right now
dude this is about to be once you figure
out this is from this is I probably saw
this on Twitter at some point but like
once you understand like what a print F
function looks like you know you see it
and you can uh cast it aside as like
this is a print F function I don't need
to look at this again um that absolutely
happens in this industry um you know I
know what this framework looks like or I
know this is a word WordPress site and
I'm just going to cast it aside or look
at extensions and that's it you know for
example um but that first time you see
something it's like yeah you have to
like put in the time to like understand
it and like going back to what you were
saying like looking for the
um trying to understand what the what
the what the quickest way is to find
bugs I really think like having a way to
search or categorize your past reports
would go a long way towards that but
then you have to have that catalog of
past reports um you know and this it
comes up with with me actually a lot
with uh um xxc type bugs like that whole
any variant of an xxc um over time I've
kind of built up like a catalog of like
past reports and it's like it's very
easy to just go in there and find
working exploits but if you search on
the Internet it's you know they might
work they might not work might only work
in certain contexts um and so you kind
of develop this catalog of things you
found and therefore can just leverage
that to go find again yeah yeah no that
that makes sense and and specifically on
targets you know like you mentioned with
the Airbnb thing I mean some targets are
just going to be vulnerable to the same
thing over and over and over again just
by nature of their software development
life cycle and their you know inner
culture decisions on how to do you know
authentication and and authorization and
that sort of thing right um and so
that's definitely good advice and and
and I guess what I mean ju a little bit
just going back to the whole volume of
attack Vector sort of vibe like I don't
mean to
to I still think this methodology could
be helpful for beginners because the
it's so easy to
get lost in in all the things you need
to study you know and all the things you
need to understand and and but I really
liked your your your scenario of like we
all needed to test a WordPress site you
know a couple times before we knew that
ah the vules are going to be in the
extensions you know yeah um and so I
don't know it's kind of a hard thing to
to normalize because I feel like should
be some way
to you know get the 8020 rule out of
this right like you know like for us to
be really thorough on a Target like we
are in the live hacking events you've
got to really go 100% but in order to
find 80% of the bugs you know with 20%
of the effort there should be some sort
of algorithm that that that should lead
us down that path but it's not
optimizing for attack VES I can see
because because that that does make
sense Joel that you know you could just
endlessly test a bunch of random things
so I don't know it's hard to nail down
yeah it's definitely it's definitely a
tricky thing I think like a lot of
different automation stuff has tried to
sort of capture that where like um
whether it's like the DNS like a lot of
that I'd say like 80% like Pro maybe not
80% but maybe like 60% is like DNS Recon
subaman takeovers like simple xss is
like vulnerable software that's been
deployed that is online like there's a
lot of that stuff that's just like easy
sort of low hangy fruit that all you
have to do is find it in in order to
exploit it um and then the rest is like
sort of like authenticated testing like
having to go deep having to like
actually understand the the the
relationships between different parts of
the application and identify how you can
you know leverage that or exploit it to
to pop oftentimes the same types of bugs
but just in a different context um I
don't know man I just think there's
something to be said for volume
as well you know like there's something
to be said for okay you know I'm going
to just go and try all the things I can
think of but maybe that's that's not the
exact exact approach all right well let
let me let's move along from a classic
Justin tangent there I'll continue to
keep on noodling on how I know I'm about
to have a 30 minute debate with Justin
about this after after he knows he knows
what's coming man um yeah you know I
don't know I feel like should be some
way but Joel we'll we'll save this for a
uh for a time when we can really uh hash
this one out um so one of the things
that I that I wanted to ask I guess sort
of tangentially related to the to the
debate that we just had there on on how
to optimize for bugs is do you think you
and this is kind of a gut feeling I've
been wanting to ask a bunch of the
people that come on the Pod how much of
your time do you think you spend
thinking about the bug versus actually
testing something so let's say you've
got a scenario where you're where you've
got like a a bug you're trying to
exploit right yep do you often just sit
back stare at the ceiling think about
the bug or do you are you constantly
iterating and trying new things and Brew
forcing this and you know that sort of
thing if you had to guess what would
your ratios be of between those
two it's really terrible honestly so I
spend far too much time throwing
everything think of at bugs like I know
I'm in trouble when I start going into
burp and like using the the hex fields
to send valid character through
something like that means I'm probably
in a little bit too deep yeah yeah but
but then like I'll more often than not
like when things aren't like super
obvious I'll find bugs when I'm not when
I'm s stealing you know or equivalent um
like that stepping back for me anyways
and thinking about how the system works
and
like you know thinking about the system
as a whole often leads system of the
better findings that I've had um you
know you're at the end of the day it's
like you're trying to you're trying to
outsmart a lot of other people who are
thinking about this security and like
yeah you're not you have your own unique
perspective but like
that's that's also like something that
other people are going to consider
potentially it's like you have to find
you have to find your angle but then
also like
um but also like find a way
to find something unique um so so on
that topic do you have any like sort of
tips that you like to use when so like
the way I'm thinking about this is
basically if I was hitting a dead wall
or a brick wall oftentimes what I would
try and do is figure out like what is
the backend running or like how to how
do I identify more parts of this
infrastructure do you have any things
that you like to do like you know just
like sort of your go-to things that you
like to try and throw in there to see if
you can figure out more about the stack
yeah and like I one of my favorite
things to try and do is to try and
understand how their development
environment works like I'll go and find
that development environment find their
origin servers like see if I can get
access to those and poke around see if
things can get reflected into prod or
vice versa um just understand more
about their deployment environment but
then also like their development
environment and even like search on
GitHub for example um for not not for
secrets so to speak but just for like
development related things for data yeah
for knowledge yeah just just anything
you could find that would like you know
you find somewhere like on GitHub like a
random IP address that happens be the
origin server and like that yeah that
can be huge like that can be all you
need for certain bugs yeah dude see I
love this so much this is this is this
is great because think listen to the way
Sam talked about that right he said I I
want I want to learn more about the
development environment so I go and find
the dev servers right and and that's not
Sam is not looking at those Dev servers
as like a separate entity of sorts right
in this in this whole system he's
looking at it as a part of the whole
right and you you know you can use that
that that extra piece right to give you
knowledge about prod or you can find
this little piece of data on GitHub that
can when you actually read the source
code or you look at the open source
libraries that they have that they're no
doubt using in their own platform right
um can you all the little pieces you
need to to get deeper and deeper and
deeper that's that's such great advice
Sam well yeah and that's also like how
you'll find like a lot of Shar secrets
between development and production and
like yeah development won't be as locked
down and so you just get access to those
Secrets more often than not you know or
you know there's also been bugs where
it's like kind of like what you're
talking about they're using something
open source but that open source Library
happens to use like a static secret
somewhere like yeah that's very common
yeah I actually man where was it I saw
recently you found something that had a
static secret it was like a a GitHub
security issue that I saw pop up
somewhere I was like where'd it go
Sam yeah yeah um I don't remember what
product it was on but I'll look it up
afterwards and I I know ex you're
talking about I don't recall s like yeah
you're gonna have to be more specific
Justin that happens to me every day I
know it was earlier this year and I just
don't recall the product all that's no
you're good um yeah so I guess the last
thing that I wanted to kind of talk to
about in sort of the hacker methodology
section
um collaboration right what what role I
mean obviously we've collaborated
together and you know collaborating with
Justin special special experience there
uh but but talk talk to me about
about talk to me about about
collaboration how it works in with your
methodology how it motivates you or how
it um you know makes you perform
different in a live hacking event or
even just in a bug bounding
context yeah like the people that I
collaborate with more often than not
it's
like I don't know I I end up putting
like higher higher expectations on
myself than the other person is proba
way to describe it like yeah I don't
want to collaborate unless I know I can
give like 110% to that Target I've
noticed that you do that I love
collaborating with you Sam well so I
just I just won't even recommend it like
if I'm like I don't know if I'm like off
doing something else I'll be like yeah
no sorry I just can't like it's not
because I want respect that you have
that like boundary though for for me I
have this really bad habit of just
saying yes to like everything so so here
I am it's December I currently have
about 15 side projects going on and
uh and I'll be doing three of them today
like yeah dude Sim it seems like you've
got some healthy boundaries man in place
with bug Bounty which is cool healthy
yeah well can you talk a little bit
about that because you know to be fair I
I think we had a conversation about this
a little bit you know you've been in
you've been in in this uh you know uh
Tech World a little longer than than
some of us hackers have and you you uh
you no but I mean you you've told me
some you you've told me some stuff that
I you
know that I appreciated and that that
you know you've learned from from the
the wisdom of being in the industry for
a little bit longer how have you I guess
gotten bug bounty to a point where you
have a better work life balance with it
and uh you know a better relationship
with bug Bounty and are able to control
those sort of obsessive Tendencies right
because it it doesn't seem like you're
you're and maybe it's it's just by by
virtue of the fact that you're not in it
every single day because you you know
have a full-time job and you kind of
distance yourself from it in that regard
but um I know you also have you know a
family and that sort of thing and and
you have other responsibilities there
and I'm just wondering how it all gets
balanced or if there's any tips you've
learned along the
way I mean for me the biggest thing is
like I I've
stopped I've stopped looking at a lot of
random programs I think is probably the
best way to describe it like I used to
you know every invite I used to be like
oh I'll poke at this and now it's like
you know you get that invite and it's
like well okay like if I have time for
this you know or like um but then like I
will try
and like when I do choose to do like a
live hacking event or like you know
especially some of the um like US
Government related bug Bounty stuff it's
like when those come up it's like okay
like I'm going to set make a point to
like set time aside for this like you
know let let folks in my life know
essentially like I'm going to be sing
these nights like doing this thing and
like especially when you're married yeah
you've got that that level of you know
communication you've got to got to get
through or else it's not going to work
yeah yeah and like you're like I'm GNA
working all day and then doing this all
night like you probably won't see me too
much you know yeah exactly yeah it's
like that or maybe you shouldn't say it
like that maybe you should say hey
sweetie you know what did you think if I
tried to earn a new car so yeah
right um yeah and I mean like I don't
know you you also like I remember the
first the first Bounty I got and this is
like the first like hack the Pentagon
thing and it was like $150 I was like
this is wild like I've never seen so
much money before in my life you know
and I was like ah yeah you know like I
guess I'll respond to this thing because
it's GNA earn me another $500 or
something that's it's you become
very it's both being jaded but then also
like yeah disassociating
the bug Bounty SP with the money to some
exent which like I don't know we're
earning good money here the day you know
we're we're in a good position to be
able to say no to certain things too as
well dude that's so good yeah like like
like having the and I think that's a a
part of the gutteral response of you
know being successful in in book bounty
in the beginning is like H I just got a
bounty like maybe I can do this more and
you know and you're just like sort of
constantly chasing that hit of the the
the you know of like the Bounty right
it's almost like gambling thing right
and um and but once you learn to control
that once you you know and and I talk
about this as little a little bit as
well is like for me it was a part of an
identity thing for me like ah like I
haven't fulfilled
my identity that I that I want you know
to be who I want to be if I'm not you
know at the top of the leaderboard every
event you know that sort of thing right
and just kind of redefining that away
has helped me um build some healthy
boundaries and it sounds like for you
you know saying no to some opportunities
you know whether it be a private PR
invite or maybe even a live hacking
event that you just you can't make it
work right now it's not going to be
healthy saying no to those things have
kind of helped you you build a more
healthy relationship with B Bounty yeah
yeah and it's also I mean to be fair one
of the benefits of like having a
full-time job and kind of doing this
like nights and weekends is like you do
you can just pause like there's you
still have health insurance and I know
you talked about this as well it's yeah
there are there are ways around this in
the US um but like you know self health
insurance you still have a paycheck
coming in like your bills are still paid
like yeah it's good and that's it's nice
to have that miss those
days I mean to to a degree I I do you
know and I love the day-to-day but for
me you know as a full-time Hunter what
that looks like is like realizing okay I
don't actually have to be working all
the time because the payoff you know the
risk is greater and the W is greater you
know um and so you know if I need to
take a couple days here and there to
like decompress and chill and you know
not be working constantly then I I
should be able to do that but you know I
I'll let you know when I ever figure I
figure that out um all right man so that
was a lot of the hacking methodology
stuff um let's let's jump back and look
look at the career a little bit because
um you know this podcast is primarily
about bug Bounty stuff um and we'll
definitely come back to more bu bounding
stuff but I also am the host of this
podcast and I have some very in I'm very
interested in uh you know Career
Development and entrepreneurialism in
particular so I'd really like to talk to
you about your career and then also the
whole thing that you did with um uh
buffer over. run um and that whole
experience so uh start from wherever
you'd like with the career thing yeah I
you know I was um kind of going back a
little bit undergrad I was a computer
system engineering I think Joel was as
well right uh well was yeah pretty much
yeah security engine engineering I I had
a security engineering major when when I
went into college so oh um yeah I'm just
gonna stop you right
there I didn't know to say that without
making you sound
old
this I'm gonna stop you right there so
Computer Engineering versus computer
science versus whatever the heck Joel
did um what what are your thoughts on
that and what are the ways you think
it's impacted your career I so I
actually dual measured with math and I
thought I was going to be a
cryptographer yeah and I found that the
computers engineering courses were
pretty straightforward and I really
struggled with the math courses so I was
like I should go and do this computer
thing um but you know honestly I think
like really any of these will give you a
good background um you know and I think
that that's like learning the
fundamentals will get you a lot of the
way to being able like really easily
pivot into bug bount the bug bount SI if
you want to um you know for me
like starting bug Bounty stuff was less
about learning the security side of it
and more about learning how burp site
worked yeah D yeah I totally see like so
many people who are like technology
adjacent who are like I don't know how
to get started and it's like do you see
something you don't know what it is just
look it up and like start following
every rabbit hole that you see and
that's the best way to get started is
just like take one step and just like
slide down the hill yeah and and and
also like you said Sam you know but it
can also you see a lot of people that
aren't technical they just know how to
use burp site and know how to find idors
and know you know have a basic
understanding yeah of how the browser
works right you know and you'll find
your xsss your your idors your C surfs
your you know Access Control issues and
that's more than enough to pay the bills
if you know those four vul types idor
xss surf access control or client side
implementation of access
controls I mean you can make a lot of
money yeah and another thing that you
can do is you can kind of Target those
as well so you can like if you say you
work in some industry that's like maybe
a little more obscure but it's still
technology adjacent you probably have
experience interfacing with some
software that like most people don't use
and so you can probably find
vulnerabilities in that way better than
other people can because you're used to
this software you might even already
kind of know a vulnerability and not
realize it's a vulnerability and it's
just like oh yeah this just kind of like
works this way it's like it's probably
not supposed to work that way um yeah so
so I'd recommend like if you you know if
you have experience with that with that
kind of stuff like try and see if they
have a program or see if they have a
security team and you know try and find
vulnerabilities because that's also a
good place to start 100 per. yeah yeah
umor yeah sorry sorry Sam for the
interruption I just you know the the
computer science versus computer
engineering thing is kind of close to my
heart because I see you know people like
um you and Joel that have a little bit
lower level understanding of some of the
stuff that I'm missing um and I've had
to claw that back uh you know since I've
graduated because my CS program was
focused entirely on programming it was
like 100% programming and and now I'm
like I don't really understand some of
this lower level stuff and I've had to
re you know gain that knowledge as a you
know as a professional um so you know my
advice I guess to to people that want to
go to college which is a choice in and
of itself um is is to go you know
Computer Engineering or security
engineering you know degree to get that
lower level aspect yeah and I've always
kind of looked at it from like you
don't what you learned There is almost
to me anyways it was kind of irrelevant
um to what I actually ended up doing but
it was more of the exposure to all these
like different Technologies different
ways to do things and then you can apply
that later um like you know never in my
life will I ever write my assembly again
but I knew how to at some point yeah I
mean but I mean that's that's the thing
that doesn't make you scared of it
though right like if you if you talk to
a web developer right somebody like like
me years ago when whenever I was just
writing PHP and you know all that sort
of thing and talk about like assembly
it's like ah you know that's that weird
[__] like where you're like putting
stuff in registers and stuff like that
right you know it's like um you know so
it's it's intimidating and I think
exposure to it is one of the things that
that can help earlier on in your
education you know you don't need to
know how to do everything for your job
right because you're going to have to
learn a lot of it on on the job but just
that base level exposure I think is
helpful yeah and I will say like getting
one thing I wish I had taken more of
where like and I don't really even know
these existed back then where like had
to be a software Dev type courses
because I think that that would get you
much further today than a lot of the
college courses that I took yeah yeah
man yeah if we could switch it and I
I'll trade you the how how to VI
software Dev stuff from my college and
you can give me like you know OS 101 or
something like that yeah exactly um uh
all right so so College um Computer
Engineering from there where'd you go
yeah so I went to work at Cisco and um I
was doing like working on like VPN
technology the ASA firewall VPN
aggregator ah dude you're the one that
wrote All That buggy code that's getting
popped every I actually wrote almost I
wrote very minimal amount of code there
you know a lot of the work I was doing
more like integrate new platforms and
stuff um but uh no the folks there I
mean they're they're brilliant what they
do to be honest um trying to make all
that work all in a single like box is
kind of nuts um but somebody there uh
was like Hey like you like security you
should go to
Defcon um and so I guess actually kind
of backing up a little bit even further
she this is like dating myself but like
um I started listening to the Security
Now podcast like right when it first
launched yeah dude that it's twit right
yep it's fun out of that and like that
to me actually got me interested in a
lot of this um into this whole world
honestly because the way that they
explained it especially in the earlier
episodes was like very very basic it
went back to fundamentals very well
there
and I don't know I just have a huge am
of respect for them especially because
still going which is just nuts yeah dude
yeah years later man it's you were a
podcast OG because that show's been
around for forever it's like 2004 I want
to say yeah I like what's it iPod iPod
Mini or something yeah oh my gosh like
downloading it over it's amazing um but
anyway sorry going back to so I was at
Cisco someone was like hey you should go
to Defcon and so like I went there and
um I was like I have no idea what to do
like I don't really just want to go to a
talk so I walked into the like the
puzzle room and Brett was sitting right
there ah really yeah that's awesome how
nuts is that yeah
yeah um and uh yeah so we ended up like
competing for a few years like we w a
few black badges which is awesome um and
then he was like you know I think I
helped him I don't remember exactly the
timeline here but at some point I like
helped him find like a like zero day RC
and Ruby like a ruby Library um oh my
gosh he's like hey you should come to
these like life hacking
events um and so yeah you should I went
to one of them and like I was like there
I was like doing anything really like
curl commands and I was like watching
everyone use burp and I was like what is
this magic you know he's using curl he's
hacking it with curl I remember a
similar thing when I started about about
I was using like Charles and and
everybody's using this thing called burp
and I was like burp you guys should try
Charles and they were like what the hell
is Charles
no well it's like I knew exactly what
everyone was doing but I just couldn't
keep up with them you know oh yeah I
mean if you're using kurl and and
freaking inspector or Dev tools versus
burp you're gonna be in trouble yeah um
yeah and so from there I was like you
know I think I actually said to uh uh
namc was at that event and I actually
said to this is back when he worked at
hacker one um I said to him I was like
I'm going to like I'm going to get
better at this I going wi one of these
events one day and that was yeah
behold that was your superhero Arc I me
that's pretty much it to be honest you
from there it's like I went to work at
UH aai working on like ca software and
then um I helped start a red team there
kind of like part time of my job um and
that really pivoted me further into the
like security engineering world
um and then yeah a year and a half ago I
join
Google yeah no that that's a good that's
a good journey and so the CTF thing you
know you rolled in Defcon you meet you
meet Brett and then you guys just kind
of hit it off and start like popping
stuff on ctfs that's that's the that's
how you got into that space it wasn't as
much ctfs as it was like Puzzles which
is like a different world okay um but it
quickly pivoted into the bug Bing world
yeah and so talk to me about the black
badge thing like that's pretty badass
for one and I think you have multiple or
one or yeah so our team won two you have
two so how how did how that's so amazing
and how did how did the CTF come about
and who's on your team give me the Deets
it
was in retrospect like I don't know it
like doesn't like feel like a real
experience but like you know we got a
team together of like there are 10 to 13
of us and these puzzles were put on by
uh uh lost 1057 who's like the organ at
Defcon or was one of the organizers at
Defcon at the time like making the
badges and everything and so he would
put together these puzzles as well and
you know our team would compete against
other similarly sized teams and we'd
spend nothing we'd do nothing else
during Defcon like that was our Defcon
so was only Defcon like you you show up
Defcon and you get the info and then you
start hacking yeah I mean we would we
would go as far as like we would
actually you know I think I I've
actually gave a I gave a talk on on this
um part of my TLS Recon was scanning the
internet
for or origin origin story of the TLs
Recon was scanning the internet for
Secrets before the Devcon launched yeah
before deathcon launch like the we
before you're trying to like find the
the servers in advance of the oh my gosh
yeah we were successful um but uh it
turns out somebody so we were monitoring
the entire doc codes TLT yeah like
everything everything like every single
domain and somebody somehow one of the
competitor competing teams got wind of
this and they put up a fake puzzle and
we spent three days solving
this you know email email lost and say
you've won this and so he sent him an
email he's like what the hell like this
wasn't
me what the heck
yeah wow that is some that is some gray
hat [__] right there dude yeah I mean
that's nuts it certainly like freaking
AR spoofing people at a live hacking
event or something jez three days
roughly of our time where we did nothing
but saw these puzzles and like to me was
really well done but like they were all
faked if I was you I would have been
pissed I mean we're suppressed about
anything else I we're a little
disappointed but wow dude that's crazy
man what a what a what the experience um
yeah those were those were fun days um
you know I think they're the puzzle's
still around I'm not quite sure if it's
still a black badge or not um you know
I've kind of I've drifted a little bit
defon for me it's become more of like a
volunteering thing than a you know
participation thing but right right now
that that makes sense um so we'll come
back to some other career stuff but you
mentioned the TLs scanning thing talk to
me a little bit about buffer over. run
um both DNS Dot and TLS Dot and uh tell
me tell me a little bit about that
project and how it ended up
yeah so the the DNS on point was just I
would take the these are all just like
honestly these are all just engineering
efforts okay let me let me also just add
a little bit so Sam ran a service um DNS
buffer do buffer over. run and TLS
buffer over. run um these were tools
that you could use for reconnaissance so
you're saying DNS do is an endpoint
where yes they were both free um yeah
you know the the DNS end point it
um sorry I just got to
something just dropped who knows what
that was sorry so the so the DNS
endpoint uh was one where um I would
take the rapid 7 public data and I would
just index it and make it searchable
because the rapid 7 it was Project sonar
data at the time was publicly available
but you would just get these like you
know like seven gig downloads or
something absurd and they would be
published like very often um like weekly
and it was just like what saw on the
internet
essentially and so so I think that they
had like hooks into bunch of DNS
infrastructure and then they just make
it available awesome which was great and
then they realized that they could
charge for it and they start charging
for it did they yank it yeah oh yeah
they yanked it no I don't think it's
free
anymore oh my gosh I haven't looked into
that in so long it's been years yeah
like two or three years now it SS that
you can still get the
data I might have to registered for it
but I think it requires registration at
least I oh no it's actually yeah 47 74
terabyt of data you still get all
the all the stuff it was last updated uh
as early as today oh interesting okay
sorry existing open data users can sign
in for access it
says yeah I think you're right Sam yeah
yeah yeah you got to sign up for and
like request access but after that okay
they they listed all at least it was no
longer publicly available and If I
recall at the time I felt it was a
little bit sketchy like rehosting
something that you have to get that's
probably probably part of why why they
did it yeah they're like hey this guy is
making it accessible stly enough someone
is constantly pulling this
down yeah that's right um but I mean to
be fair no I was only doing like once a
week um you know I had a little
like I don't know call it Cron job or
whatever no it was the smallest VPS I
could possibly buy I went was some one
of those like European VPS hosters that
was like
you know like two EUR a month like oh
that's awesome yeah there was I don't
recall exactly which hosting provider it
was but they were European and yeah for
whatever reason it was just enough power
to run this web server it was right like
70% CPU like 100% of the time but it
stayed
up question mark and then and then after
you so what you did with DNS scrap was
you took that whole data excted it down
a little bit sorted it so it' be easy to
you know JP through the indexes and then
um and then you made it you know
supposed in htttp API for that right
yeah exactly yeah you can download like
good amount of data like 100 megabytes
fish or so at a time if you wanted to
from that endpoint and I actually ended
up putting uh at the time Cloud flare in
front of it just because like I would
get like 90 95% offload cuz everyone's
searching for like yahoo.com like oh
yeah of course everyone search the same
thing with the Recon pipelines so I was
like all right I'll but glad for in fun
of it and they offloaded like an like
just an absurd amount of data for meing
was there a lot of people who were like
hitting you as well like hitting your
apis essentially and like done the same
thing where they were like now taking
all your data and farming it into into
their own systems well so I'll talk
about that in a second with the TLs endp
point because that one was much worse
honestly so with the TLs end point I um
I implemented a system where I was
like without I don't know how much
detail I should get into here without
like I'll explain why in a second I
guess um uh but I was scanning the the
public internet for TSS and I used like
you know I have a lot of TS background
so I Ed like every trick I can think of
to make it as fast as possible um I
wrote my own like little modified
existent library to make it work oh my
God Sam what is wrong with you you know
normal things that everybody does well
that made it honestly though that made
it affordable that made it so that I
could afford to run you dude the amount
of time you spent rewriting that TLS
Library cost you more than that freaking
compute power ever would uh I don't know
I was I was scanning the entire internet
for like 20 bucks a month have you seen
the C ac2 I don't know Sam or okay so
you you rewrote a TLS did you write this
whole thing in in go or C all go yeah it
was all go okay it all go gotcha um and
so just just as quick as what I possibly
could you know um and that honestly that
made it affordable for me to run this
and then similar hosting structure where
like teeny server like with Cloud flare
in front of it and um so I was
uh sorry lost my TR of thought there no
no you're good so so you built up you
built up that that extra you know fast
TLS scanning you're pumping that into a
database and then and then serving that
via the API so people can query against
T certificates that are popping up over
the public internet yeah exactly yeah
sorry um yeah and so like this for for
me anyways this day was very valuable CU
like you know there's exposed origin all
over the place um you know there's a lot
of like end points without DNS routing
necessarily or like internal DNS routing
that you find valid tlss for and you
know especially I wasn't validating any
the tlss so that there was
um there were a lot of like self signed
stuff whatever ter sorry yeah self
signed shs that exist on the internet
for like Dev instances of things and you
know finding all those is extremely
valuable like as a hunter and like that
led to a lot of bugs like a significant
number of my finds for years honestly
wow and so I then realized as I was like
running this I eventually realized that
folks were using this data and reselling
it like I essentially put up like a you
know a rough terms of service and every
request down response downloaded that
was like like please don't resell this
yeah it's all sold like don't don't do
legal things with this and don't resell
it and I found a bunch of folks were
reselling I think like three or four
different different companies and like
oh man how did how did you find that
they were reselling it um a couple cases
someone reached out to me and then a
couple other cases like it was just like
somebody posted like oh like look at all
this data like and it listed their
sources and it's like buff Rover Run was
one of their sources you should have
just put like Sam BBY is is amazing.
example.com in all your data sets and
then start looking and seeing if any of
them have it in there well yeah I mean
there's there's you know a lot of less
ethical I could have done with that like
embedding fake IP addresses in there but
I didn't it just didn't seem like the
right thing to do like even calling
somebody out it's like a lot of these
were like startups and stuff and they
might not even know um or like the other
thing too is like in a lot of cases
these are in other countries so there's
no legal recourse um sure so long story
short I was like okay I'm GNA go like
round three which is well I guess
roundout four which sh this all down
roundout three was uh turns into a real
product yeah and so
um I spent you know I I finally spent a
little bit ofs
budget I think I was spending
like
uh probably like a few hundred bucks a
month on AOS and like turned this into
like a whole real pipeline like
everything was much faster it was
getting the internet way faster and then
I used a rapid API to actually turn this
into like a production API endpoint and
yeah it turns out like a bunch of
companies then immediately sign up for
it so like a data data reselling company
you know sign up for it at like an
Enterprise level so there were there was
actually interest in this um how much
were you charging uh the Enterprise tier
was only like 250 a
month I yeah underpriced that one a
little bit didn't you a little bit um
but still like that's still like pretty
good right like I think like again we're
we're a little like jaded abstract but
$250 a month per customer is like pretty
soft no it is good it is good not to not
to diminish that at all but like yeah
but again like right on this scale of
like Enterprise applications I mean
people charge 250,000 a month but it's
like you know crazy um yeah yeah so from
there uh you know I run a few customers
but like I also deployed some much
bigger scanny servers there's a there
there's a web host that exists that will
sell you bare metal servers
that they don't it's not that they don't
care what you do with them it's that
they that's a good way to don't say it
like that
it's that they're very scanner friendly
um they're a scann friendly host um
sure they're yeah they're I've got a
host like that too in they're located in
Sweden the thing they're like a us I
don't I don't fully understand how they
operate um to be blunch um so name them
but uh like well hey man you know Port
scanning isn't illegal I don't I don't
understand why everyone freaks out but
like Port scanning is
legal yeah Port scanning legal know I I
just yeah I don't maybe they just send
their abuse email to you know toid
yeah whatever they do about it um you
know I was paying them like $500 a month
for like a a bare metal server um to
scan much faster so I was getting
results
on the entire internet in 24 hours and
certain subsets of it in like an hour to
20 minutes depending on that's great
that's fast yeah so it was like almost
instantaneous like I would see
um and yeah I me that to me was
extremely valuable but then uh yeah the
both getting this job but then also um
the like support of all that
infrastructure became a little bit much
so I I reach out over to a friend who
was at the time over at um record
future and they ended up uh purchasing
the whole
thing it was it wasn't like amazing
money but it was still good money so I
was very happy to hand it off to them
very good
yeah no it's cool to to it's definitely
on my bucket list to do like some little
little project like that turn it into
like the software as a service and then
you know eventually exit it so that
that's I love to hear people doing that
what what year was it when you exited do
you know oh this is last year oh okay
okay yeah around the time I on Google
yeah yeah very cool awesome yeah that's
really really interesting so final
little section we had here was just
talking about Google and uh your
experience there and the whole um you
know program that you guys have in place
um so talk to me a little bit about your
current role at Google and your
involvement with the bug Bounty side of
it yeah so um I my time at Google is
split between the the bug bount program
and then
um uh what we refer to as like kind of
like product Security reviews um so you
know looking at signs or things about to
launch for their security um you you
know making sure it's good to go or
answering any questions that the team
things might have um but then the bug
Bounty side um I am part of the so it's
backing up the way that our bug b
program works is like our uh the at
least on the Google bug b program um we
have a rotation of bug hunters or or
security Engineers sorry who will accept
reports from bu hunters and uh we we'll
we'll TR them on like a weekly basis um
and then uh we we essentially take turns
as troser for the week um you know I
think that this and so sorry to answer
your question I'm on that rotation but
then I also help out on the um you know
on the help with the overall Program
help to try to make it better um sure
yeah yeah that that that's got to be
interesting man being on the on the
triage side especially for you know an
attack surface as big as Google like
that's got to be nuts before you you
started like working at Google or I
guess maybe the the same thing but
before you were in the rotation before
you started working there whatever had
you hacked on Google at all like did you
have any precursor knowledge about like
what vulnerabilities looked like what
the infrastructure was like anything
like that um yes and no to some extent
uh like I had found um some box in
Chrome actually okay yeah again it no
big deal all
right off to the side like yeah just
couple couple chromium bugs you know uh
but I didn't actually I don't think I
had I have to look through my email I
don't think I actually had any on Google
proper because like the minimization
actually really slowed me down we
actually just released a uh burp
extension that will do Proto de
compiling for you yeah dude freaking
love
that we mentioned it on the Pod a couple
weeks back when it first came out um and
I was like dang There Goes My moat
because uh Lin and I sort of like you
know built that exact same tool except
it's not as good as yours uh you know a
couple weeks back when we were hacking
on Bard um and so yeah no I was glad to
see that drop though because that really
opens accessibility up a lot yeah that
was that was really my what was holding
me back anyways when I was looking at
Google originally
um you know I think like honestly being
on the being on the trash team like you
really do see see just how many
different Services we have um yeah we
get we get bugs from everywhere Place
yeah yeah can you talk a little bit uh
sorry real quick Joel um C can you talk
a little bit about that extension and
like like were you writing it I know I
know you're one of the collab
collaborators on the but like were you
like the one hands on the keyboard
writing it and could you talk a little
bit about the the structure that Google
uses in their request that makes it kind
of
tricky yeah um so uh that extens was
actually authored by a in inter cat over
the summer oh great so we're just
getting around to release it now
what a cool project yeah yeah um you I
think it it worked out really well we
actually ended up um it turns out that
somebody uh or the the protuff team
actually had released a tool called uh
protoscope I believe it was called that
kind of did exactly what we needed and
so we kind of just glued the Chrome the
burp extension bits onto that um and it
actually end up working out really well
nice yeah that's cool but uh the reason
that it's so complic well the reason
that Proto Buffs are complicated um is
that you don't necessarily know the
definition going over the
wire exactly so the when the JavaScript
gets compiled it knows the definition
but the minifi JavaScript you're not
given the definition of the protuff and
that can make
um request request and response
manipulation very difficult uh in
websites that use it right yeah and what
I had noticed like there were maybe two
websites that I really were like my
go-tos that were able to do essentially
this like the Proto like taking s just
like a hex or b64 blob of protuff data
and just saying like here's what the the
type structure looks like here's what
the the field indexes are good luck um
you know and it's awesome that this is
now like an official tool and a c tool
and now also a burp extension so that
you can sort of tie this into all your
own tooling and all that all that other
good fun stuff and uh sort of lower that
that bar for for hacking on Google which
is so super super awesome to see yeah
there's also a few others in there also
like if there's something the extension
can't do you know there are there are a
few other options listed um you know
there were definitely uh we definitely
looked at those um as we were as we were
implementing this um you know for like
just a both both to just see how they
worked but then also to
um uh we wanted to we wanted to provide
that list just to give folks a choice
right so so with the extension that that
loopin built uh and that we were using
on Bard um essentially it would kind of
do some deobfuscation and like you know
formatting and that sort of thing but at
the end of the day you're still not
getting like parameter names and stuff
like that you're still you're just
getting like okay here's an array you
know we know that this is like you know
a string you know like and like for
protuff like the names are completely
like decorative like it like
structurally wise like all it cares
about is what what is the index like the
field ID number and what type is it and
beyond that like you could name it
whatever you want it's really just like
you know extra okay so so for those of
you with because I hacked [__] for like
a week so I've got a very rudimentary
understanding of it but the the
um
the part of the reversing process then
becomes what is this what the heck is
this thing right like this request now
added field 19 what is field 19 where
does this come from yeah exactly so so
you're you're really you're spending a
you're much more blind you're you're
trying to sort of create um deductions
about how the request is actually being
formatted and what you know numeric ID
is being used where what string is being
used where um any any tips or for that
or is it really just got to you know
we're getting a little bit closer to um
a little bit more difficult hacking
where you're just sitting there and just
trying to make sense of even what you're
seeing let alone trying to figure out
how the back end Works um I mean
the if you see you know the one tip I'll
give actually is like if you see missing
Fields try and putting something in
there yeah yeah like stuff that's out of
order well you'll get stuff out of order
but you also get field numbering when
you um when you decompile and recompile
it and so like I don't know if you have
like Fields like one two and five like
what are three and four three and four
yeah yeah yeah okay that's interesting
because because you know uh also one of
the problems I ran into was that it it
doesn't give ver most errors ever right
so it's like error five and I'm like no
like not error five again you know and
so it's good to hear that like actually
just you know trying to insert stuff
different indexes may actually do
something um because you know it could
in my in my head you know I was thinking
they probably have something very
specific they're looking for and if I
just if I do anything besides like
change the ID numbers or you know
anything like that it's gonna heck
everything up yeah I mean it really you
know it depends on the application
sorry dang it yeah I was I wanted the I
wanted the Silver Bullet Sam like yeah
become a Google employee and read the FR
of us yeah s's like yeah dude I don't
have to deal with this [__] I got the
Proto files you know like I got the I
got the definitions on this side we have
hired Bug Hunter before I think eel
who's who's won a bunch of like the
cloud Awards we hired him very cool yeah
we'll have to chat about that after um
so I guess so you know you're on the
triage team you see a lot of a lot of
bugs coming through there
um any crazy stories any crazy stories
you want to share or are we diving too
deep into the the known the things that
we're not allowed to probe about well so
this is like this is the interesting
part is that I can't talk about these
bugs but as bug reporters we don't hold
folks to ndas so you're welcome to talk
about your bugs like active
bugs yeah wow that's crazy man that's
that's kind of nuts I've heard that
before if you say you're G to disclose
we'll send you standardized closer
notice I'm not going to attempt to
paraphrase it but um yeah we're not
going to
T wow that's really Co that's really
cool yeah that's one of the few programs
out there that really like actually lets
you do that pretty freely because almost
every other big program is like all
right if you want to get paid for it
then Mom's the Word you know well yeah
we'll also I mean if you read blog post
about it too like we'll like retweet it
and stuff and oh wow that's clutch
they're even going to promote it yeah
yeah you know we want we want more folks
finding bugs and yeah uh but uh
I will say actually one of the one of
the mar TR parts that came through um
and so sorry backing off I guess um
so the I don't know if you've paid
attention recently but like the over the
past year I guess we' we've lost
probably not we've lunched a lot of uh
We've lunched a bunch of different um uh
kind of uh different bug Bounty programs
is the best way to describe them within
Google yeah I wanted to ask about that
because there's like you know the the
one where it's like you get a bunch of
uh you any app above 100 million you
know installs that's in scope for Google
The Google plays you know thing and
there's the vrp and then there's some AI
stuff so like there's a bunch going on
well so the one in particular that I
want to call out is um the abuse vrp and
this is something that like I didn't
before join I didn't have a lot of
insight into um and it's actually really
interesting so like when we are
um when we are like rewarding payments
through the Google vrp we'll actually at
the same time do the abuse therapy
because often there are there are bugs
where it's applicable to both and we'll
just like rear whichever one's highest
what is the abuse VP yeah I was going to
say like what falls
under so to use the example um recently
somebody reported that uh they received
like a really convincing fishing email
that um and this is like this they
actually wrote about this publicly so I
can talk about it um it it became a
problem with the BMI
protocol um it had some sort of like
email I this is pushing the limits of
what I uh know about this but um it's
some sort of uh email user
identification system I've never even
heard of this brand brand indicators for
message identification it's it's kind of
like SPF or dkim or um Demar or one of
those like I guess it's just an
additional sort of security
layer their additional DNS Bimi brand uh
brand what was it brand and uh
indicators for message
identification wow and so somebody
reported a problem that they like
received like a really convincing
fishing email through this um and like
that's not you know fishing emails don't
like quite fit cleanly under the rules
of our vrp necessarily and but under the
abuse vrp like this is like a very
clearcut like this can be used to abuse
our products and so um like we accepted
through that but then like
you know I think that actually resulted
in like RFC updates like they they
weren't they weren't aware that this
could be an attack I don't recall the
exact details but it did it did get some
news back uh a few months ago so it
sounds like kind of the distinction is
like more like re repurposing intended
functionality or at least like featured
functionality for like a bad purpose
versus something that's like a security
vulnerability and maybe they kind of
like overlap a little bit but like one
is more like classical than the other is
that is that kind of just exactly yeah I
think that's the where I would to look
at it like you know like there's there's
things that are cleanly technical
security vulnerabilities like n RC would
be a clean security vulnerability or
like uh clean abuse like you can I don't
know like steal money from somebody yeah
let me let me let me read this really
quickly it says okay note in addition
significant abuse related methodologies
are also in scope for this program if
the reported attack scenario displays a
design or implementation issue in Google
products that could lead to significant
harm an example of an abuse related
methodology would be a technique by
which an hacker is able to manipulate
the rating score of listing on Google
Maps by submitting a sufficiently large
volume of fake reviews that go
undetected by our abuse
system that's really cool super cool
yeah and so we get we get a lot of
reports where
like you know we forward it to that team
yeah I imagine so so I wanted to ask
like because Google's so huge and you
guys probably receive a lot of reports
um how do you go sort of about like
drawing the line for like this is stuff
we don't care about because I can
imagine that there you can you can you
know rework all your bugs in one way or
another and make it so that like
technically it falls under some form of
either abuse or technical security issue
and how do you stop like that from
overloading the inter internal teams
with like lots of little nitpicky things
that don't really like that that maybe
they should fix but not doesn't need to
happen tomorrow right like you know what
I mean yeah I mean we have a lot of
automation on our side that helps us
that especially with that first level of
like look at the report like do we even
own this
URL
um yeah actually I got a I got when I
submitted a bug it's like I got an email
back saying hey uh by Google magic we
know this like within like two minutes
of me submitting the bug it's like by
Google magic we know that this is a
valid report or like like that oh wow
that's kind of crazy like so we do have
a I need some of that magic seriously uh
so I should preface this by saying well
I should preface this by saying that
security Engineers will still look at
every report that really impacts the
order which which we look at things uh
but we do have like a first pass like
machine learning uh system that will'll
look at a re report and knows what's
previously been valid and invalid um I
should also say just before we go any
further that like anything I say here
the rules Pages take precedent um in
case I make any mistakes yeah that's
that's fair that's fair you know if you
go under the you said on the ctbb
podcast that I could submit fishing
emails but then so then if you go to on
the bug Hunters website if you go under
um the invalid reports section um yeah
there are a few a few different
categories there which actually often
will catch folks offu guard um the one
big one especially is um open redirects
like there's a few places where we have
intentional open redirects
that do have security properties yeah um
those are those are intentional um and
we often get reports around those I I uh
I saw a tweet a while back that was like
Hey I can only you know I'm trying to
get this open redirect to work but I can
only redirect to like the site and
google.com and I was like ah you're in
luck because slamp you hit slamp with
that open redirect and it'll uh you know
redirect you to whatever domain you want
um and you you know that's that's just a
a gadget that's been in place for a
while and this is just a comment on a
you know on a Twitter response and
everyone was like like retweet like you
know like I spend so much time like
writing like very thoroughly thought
through sing comment yeah very very
thorough responses and then this one
just like blows up because Google's got
an open redirect they won't fix it's
like come on I would when they won't fix
I would look on the about page to
understand more of our logic yeah let
let me be clear I don't think it's a
problem I don't think it's a problem
because Google you know well I I I guess
let me let me let me challenge that a
little bit I think it is I don't have
all the contacts in your organization I
think it's a little bit irresponsible to
to do something like that um because I
use open redirect in Chains like every
day you know um and so ideally that
would be fixed but the thing is Google
is a is a you know a search engine and
the the part of the business case is
redirecting users you know to things so
um I'm sure there's a perfectly valid
bit you know use case word on your side
but I will say I've used that
redirecting chains many times I will say
also though that there are and once
again like look at the invalid reports
redir page for a lot more technical
information around this I probably
should read before I join
this no I have it open I I'll we'll put
a link down below okay yeah yeah we'll
um there are a lot of cases where we do
accept those um oh really interesting
there's like you know JavaScript
redirects obviously um yeah but like
ones that aren't intentional might get
rewarded interesting and I look at that
page once again okay all right yeah well
we'll add it um yeah JavaScript redir
client side redir we've talked about
this plenty of times on the Pod but um
there there
is a lot of use cases with that
especially with uh with the onset of um
uh same side cookies and just whether or
not things are going to be s cookies
depending on where the request
originated from and when you do a client
side redirect via JavaScript you um you
really you know you're sending different
cookies along if you had just done it
from a third party uh top level nav so
well actually I know sorry I made like a
little more like uh open redirect to
cross scripting but yeah oh okay gotcha
open redirect to cross scripting okay
well it's interesting you know
JavaScript level redirects I'd think
that I'd be surprised if you guys
accepted those but I I also wouldn't be
surprised in that there I think yeah I
actually sorry I don't know if we accept
those I really I really didn't mean the
the you know the JavaScript URI like the
oh the redirect to yeah sure client
redirect and where you can snag it via
crossy scripting yeah no that makes
sense um well that's cool man yeah
there's a lot of different there's a lot
of I'm on the the page for I guess bug
hunters. google.com and there's a ton of
different uh programs here on the left
hand side Android and Google device
security reward program all the way to
alphabet program to open source to OS
fuzz or OSS fuzz so like there's a ton
of stuff here um so that's a big job you
got going on there Sam because we got we
have a large team and like we want to we
want to reward good vulnerabilities um
you know I think the if you want to see
some other cool ones some of my
favorites have been on the
um the there's yearly there in the past
years have been Cloud uh Cloud rewards
for like the best
gcp Stu nice um you know those are
always like super creative um there have
been some great rups there as well very
nice um you added something to the doc
here hacking Google and it's like a like
it's it's one of the coolest things I've
ever seen to be honest like I I uh I
love seeing BR Embrace hacking like this
by the way dude this was not on my radar
at all and we're going to link this down
below but it apparently it's like a you
know a
multi-series uh almost like a
documentary of like essentially hacks
that have happened with Google you know
and and hacking related stuff at Google
um super well produced yeah they went
allow with this talk to me about that I
mean and it's only a year old and
there's like millions and millions and
millions of views on it yeah um yeah
this I probably can best describe this
as like this is what I show my
grandparents to what I
do like it awesome it tries to put into
like you know it's just something that's
publicly consumable like you know by
everybody like what what we do as
security Engineers you know it talks
about a bunch of different teams um the
one that I linked to there is the one on
our uh bani
Team yeah is that the let me see episode
four because I only I only got through
some of them yeah episode episode four
that was the one I wild I yeah it's
really well done it's I really like that
Series yeah the first one operation
Aurora I I I watched that one I was like
this is amazing and then I clicked right
on the bug Hunters one and then I
realized I got to go record the podcast
so no that's great I'm going to go back
and check that out also they've got a
project zero section as well which is
such a cool um part of Google um so
definitely definitely check out the uh
hacking Google series um dude I think
that we're already at an hour 30 that
kind of concludes what I had on the uh
on the list here um did you have
anything else you wanted to shout out or
talk about uh before we we wrap the Pod
no uh thank you for having thank you all
for having me on here you know this is
experience of course man you can find
Sam on on Twitter Irby Sam and I don't
know do you even use your LinkedIn I've
got it here but uh he doesn't even use
LinkedIn so just find him on Twitter uh
or x b Sam with two v's um Sam thanks
for coming on and sharing your knowledge
man and uh looking forward to our next
collab where you give it 110% and uh you
know yes all right man talk to you soon
peace
peace all right all right I I ended the
podcast before Sam talked to us about
cool bugs so I mentioned um on the Sam
old podcast a while back that uh Sam was
one of the first people that introduced
me to
xslt um and so Sam I was wondering if
you could share a little bit about that
bug and yeah just kind of talk to us
about that yeah so this was at this is
like one of the first life hacking
events I attended and uh there was this
endpoint that accepted
um it was XML but it wasn't XML it's Xs
T which is like a data transformation
language okay so it accepted uh xslt
directly yes um but it it would accept
like it was like you would accept like
your your input and then the exil to
transform it with um and so it's one of
those like uh business logic type
languages that like well I'm probably
butchering this for exsl experts um but
it's one of those business logic type
languages that allow you to transform
data kind of arbitrarily and like
a userfriendly way like you know
somebody who can write an Excel document
can go and write this XML format um and
so apparently after as I found out like
actually a lot of folks of folks at the
life acing event found this end point
and just kind of did a simple like XC
payload and kind of called it a day um
yep I decided to spend a bunch of extra
hours digging into this classic classic
Sam so what I actually ended up doing
was like I actually went to the function
reference and I Ste through every
function
uh I'm yeah hold up what so so so you
you did you take up like did you somehow
leak the library name and then set up
your own local instance and then hook up
a debugger I mean whoa whoa whoa whoa
whoa uh what did we do
there
yes I think it was open source I think
it was open source so I'm pretty sure I
saw my own instance of this uh just test
it out um but then like I also I just
want to I just want to highlight how Sam
was like yeah so anyway I thought
thought this was interesting so I just
you know put a break point on the debug
I was like
what many hours in after trying many
different things like there like there's
there are a fair number of public xslt
exploits and like they seem to be fairly
patched um so I did so yeah I if I
recall correctly I de said in my own
instance and this is like 2019 no this
is even earlier this would have been
2018 or 2017 um and yeah I just stepped
through every function saw what it did
and then I eventually realized that like
you could string like two or three of
these functions together to get like a
really cool
um uh lfi Gadget and I believe I also
had an RC Gadget in there as well yes
you did but I just remember that because
like I was like there were some
limitations around it like it was there
was a couple I don't recall exactly what
the limitation was but like I kept
trying to explain it further and I
couldn't like maybe I couldn't like
pivot to route or something like that
and so I actually gave a presentation
that event afterwards like showing this
off which is probably where you remember
from and I was like oh yeah you know I'm
like really disappointed in this bug you
know I thought I could take it further
and I I think it was uh doggy G was like
dude like you still got a crit like
yeah chill it out like he just reading
you know arbitrary files from production
on a multi-billion dollar company like
just just accept it take the dub you
know yeah dude uh xslt is a really
interesting thing that I'm looking
forward to diving into a little bit more
when I find you know something that
takes it I'm sorry no go go say it
um there's like this whole class of like
business logic languages and things that
aren't really ever meant to be exposed
to the internet and when they are result
in really scary things and it's like
there have been efforts to lock these
down but like often they weren't really
ever built to be locked down and so like
they they're just going to be they're
going to continue to be kind of like a
source of vulnerabilities going forward
and you know I think that that's a great
area for more original research I mean
we even see this with with XML right
like XML is a data markup language like
why does it have this functionality to
like read local files and send HTTP
requests right um so really it it is
cool anytime you see the opportunity to
do something like like that where you're
actually parsing some type of code you
know um on the server side big money
there MH very cool man all right well I
I wanted to get that last little
explanation in hopefully we didn't lose
any viewers at the first uh at the first
false end but um thanks for coming on
man and thanks for sharing about that bu
content this is sweet awesome peace
peace